<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Numinous Bodywork</title>
    <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Numinous Bodywork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://numinousbodywork.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;720-500-5482&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:numinousbodywork@mgail.com&#34;&gt;numinousbodywork@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;address&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2945 Center Green Court, Suite H, Boulder, CO 80301&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d97762.13655711975!2d-105.31018910946726!3d40.029288713193296!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x876b8d4e278dafd3%3A0xc8393b7ca01b8058!2sBoulder%2C+CO!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1487522437880&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d97762.13655711975!2d-105.31018910946726!3d40.029288713193296!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x876b8d4e278dafd3%3A0xc8393b7ca01b8058!2sBoulder%2C+CO!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1487522437880&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>forms</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/forms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://numinousbodywork.com/forms/dummy-form.pdf&#34;&gt;Download Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>readings</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/interests/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:01:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VHS next level coloring book, pour-over venmo plaid mumblecore blog. Green juice meditation vegan, tofu try-hard pok pok yr viral ennui glossier freegan. Raclette mlkshk tacos, jianbing enamel pin pop-up iPhone cliche meggings cornhole hexagon pok pok 3 wolf moon kale chips plaid. Shoreditch next level pop-up, lumbersexual man braid 3 wolf moon pabst microdosing pinterest tofu wayfarers vice. Edison bulb seitan mustache hot chicken ethical, taxidermy gentrify authentic meditation XOXO brooklyn chicharrones franzen street art. Cred activated charcoal kinfolk iceland food truck literally. Dreamcatcher bitters four dollar toast, plaid vegan 8-bit flannel messenger bag flexitarian swag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fanny pack you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of them 3 wolf moon, mustache roof party humblebrag kickstarter asymmetrical pok pok YOLO pinterest sriracha echo park vape waistcoat. Aesthetic listicle poke, chambray neutra hot chicken plaid craft beer. Cardigan kinfolk small batch, tattooed roof party green juice asymmetrical bitters bushwick selfies austin raclette post-ironic. Gentrify kitsch activated charcoal cardigan direct trade, la croix distillery. 8-bit keytar tousled next level put a bird on it. IPhone intelligentsia flannel, cold-pressed occupy taxidermy beard lumbersexual semiotics. Everyday carry tumeric twee, quinoa chia prism microdosing skateboard bitters 3 wolf moon franzen VHS edison bulb truffaut pug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brooklyn microdosing polaroid seitan lo-fi. Franzen flexitarian pitchfork kinfolk, williamsburg hell of cred literally sustainable tofu gluten-free. Dreamcatcher heirloom ethical, cold-pressed thundercats street art authentic quinoa selfies post-ironic put a bird on it occupy leggings sriracha. Vegan chambray organic deep v godard. Food truck chicharrones XOXO, irony raw denim mustache af polaroid kogi bushwick. Vexillologist ramps put a bird on it, cliche salvia vice raclette meh schlitz pabst poke lomo celiac af yr. Squid godard hoodie, tilde next level 8-bit gochujang edison bulb enamel pin pop-up aesthetic retro poutine man bun yr.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Mindfulness Practices that Improve Your Heart Health</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/five-mindfulness-practices-that-improve-your-heart-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/five-mindfulness-practices-that-improve-your-heart-health/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;New research is finding that self-awareness practices improve physical health as well as promoting mental wellbeing. Those who practice mindfulness show rtoms of anxiety and depression, perceived stress, blood pressure, and body mass index. They are also less likely to have negative indicators for heart disease, including smoking and lack of physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five mindfulness practices that will boost your heart health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-yoga&#34;&gt;1 | Yoga&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you realize that while you’re lying in savasana, somewhere between sleep and wakefulness, that you are actually decreasing your risk for heart disease?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many styles of yoga don’t have the same blood-pumping burn of a long run or circuit training, yoga still provides the same benefit to heart health gained through aerobic exercise. Not only can a regular yoga practice help you feel calmer and more balanced, but it can also help your heart. Nearly 80 percent of people who practice yoga also report reduced stress as a result, according to the 2012 National Health Interview Survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try it for yourself&lt;/em&gt;. You can find a yoga studio near where you live and take a class, or you can practice in the comfort of your own home. All you’ll need are a yoga mat, some loose-fitting stretchy clothing, and a guided yoga sequence (you can find an abundance of these online). If you decide to stick with a regular yoga practice, props like a yoga block or strap can come in handy when attempting more challenging poses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-massage&#34;&gt;2 | Massage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you call to book your next massage, you’ll be happy to know that you’re not just scheduling time to relax your aching muscles, you’re preventing heart disease, too. Massage therapy has proven to be an effective measure for lowering blood pressure and relieving chronic stress, both important indicators for heart disease. Chronic stress can potentially damage your arteries and increase blood pressure, so the stress-reducing effects of massage can have a direct impact on preventing future cardiovascular problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try it for yourself&lt;/em&gt;. Schedule a massage to receive the benefits of improved circulation, reduced stress and muscle tension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-meditation&#34;&gt;3 | Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By increasing awareness and reducing overall stress and anxiety, meditation can allow the body to adapt better to physical stress and strengthen the circulatory system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23149426&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that Transcendental Meditation &amp;trade; reduced the risk of mortality, heart attack, and stroke in patients with coronary heart disease, due to lowering their blood pressure and reducing their psychosocial stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try it for yourself&lt;/em&gt;. Taking a 10 or 15 minute “vacation” from the stress of your day can work wonders for easing your anxiety and creating opportunities for more restful sleep, which is also essential for the body’s natural healing process. You can use deep breathing techniques, a repetitive sound like a chime or gong, or even a guided meditation recording to help you maintain focus and avoid unwanted distractions. Start small, with just a few minutes a day in a tranquil space in your home, and gradually increase the length and quality of your meditation over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-gratitude&#34;&gt;4 | Gratitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a grateful perspective on life, whether in a spiritual sense or toward those around you, can help reduce your risk of heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study found lower levels of inflammation— an important indicator for plaque buildup that can cause heart disease— in heart failure patients who kept a gratitude journal and reported a high level of gratefulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it for yourself. Spend 5 minutes before you get out of bed each morning scanning your mind for 3 people or experiences that bring joy into your life. Pause, reflect on why they are important to you and then express your gratitude for them. Then write down those 3 things or people that you are grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-mindful-eating&#34;&gt;5 | Mindful Eating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the last food that you ate? If you can remember what it was, do you also remember the flavor profile of it, and the sensation of the food inside of your mouth as you chewed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t recall these details, you’re not alone. The average person doesn’t pause to make eating a mindful practice, but a growing body of research indicates that doing so could have significant health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowing down the daily habit of eating to make it a mindful practice can help reduce risk factors for heart disease and type 2 Diabetes while also contributing to weight loss. That’s according to a 2016 study in the journal Obesity, which followed a group of 194 obese adults while they implemented a healthy eating and exercise program, with a select group given mindfulness training as well. In addition to achieving greater weight loss than the control group, the mindfulness group also reduced their physiological risk factors for heart disease and type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it for yourself: The next time you eat, slow yourself down. Make sure you actually sit down instead of eating on the go. Set a timer for 20 minutes, being sure to use the full amount of time to eat your meal. Take small bites of food, and chew them well. Pause to look at and enjoy each bite that you eat. See how being more aware of what you use to nourish your body changes the way you perceive hunger and satiety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Balance your Heart (Xin) with Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/how-to-balance-your-heart-xin-with-traditinal-chinese-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/how-to-balance-your-heart-xin-with-traditinal-chinese-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you think about improving your heart health, your mind may jump immediately to healthy diet and exercise. With the heart typically described by modern medicine as little more than a mechanical pump, it’s hard to imagine an emotional, spiritual and physical approach to improving your heart health, much less one based on science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM), the heart (xin) is known as the master of all the other organs, and is the source of both physical and mental life. The xin guides all other organs of the body into proper balance, but only when it is perfectly balanced itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xin can be translated as heart, intention, or center; however the full meaning goes beyond the physical heart to describe the place in our body where the spirit and mind reside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In TCM, the heart houses the spiritual aspect of the mind, known as shen. Shen is essential because according to Chinese medical principles dating back over 2,000 years, the physical and emotional heart are not separate; they are interwoven partners in a balanced body.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>