<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Numinous Bodywork</title>
    <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Numinous Bodywork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://numinousbodywork.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/contact/</guid>
      <description> If you have any questions at all please feel free to reach out
Phone: 907.419.5327
Email: numinousbodywork@gmail.com
Address: 2945 Center Green Court, Suite H Boulder, CO 80301
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rates &amp; Forms</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/rates-and-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/rates-and-forms/</guid>
      <description> Rates 
   75 Minute Session Sliding Scale 8 Series Approach     $120 $80-120 $800    At Home Appointments are available, please contact for further information.

Forms No Available Forms </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interests</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 23:23:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/interests/</guid>
      <description> Michael Hamm - Neurofascia International Fascia Research Congress International Association of Structural Integrators Heart Math Bruce Lipton- The Biology of Belief Hugh Milne- The Heart of Listening Jean-Pierre Barral- Visceral Manipulation Whitney Lowe- Orthopedic Massage David Gorman- The Body Moveable Sacred Geometry  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:01:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Richard Cote Directo, LMT   Numinous Bodywork comes from clinical massage practice combining myofascial and structural techniques, orthopedic assessments and applications, movement practices, and osteopathic traditions. Additionally, various movement practices have informed my understanding how the body works.
I consider my bodywork an approach rather than a modality. When treating someone, no one technique reigns. My studies have been influenced by Visceral Manipulation, CranioSacral Therapy, Shiatsu, the Trager Approach, Myofascial Release, Neuromuscular Therapy, Clinical Massage and Injury Treatment, Structural Bodywork, Swedish Massage, Abhyanga, Orthopedic Massage, and Neurofascial Release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>