<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine on Numinous Bodywork</title>
    <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/categories/medicine/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in medicine on Numinous Bodywork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://numinousbodywork.com/categories/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Balance your Heart (Xin) with Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
      <link>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/how-to-balance-your-heart-xin-with-traditinal-chinese-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numinousbodywork.com/writings/how-to-balance-your-heart-xin-with-traditinal-chinese-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you think about improving your heart health, your mind may jump immediately to healthy diet and exercise. With the heart typically described by modern medicine as little more than a mechanical pump, it’s hard to imagine an emotional, spiritual and physical approach to improving your heart health, much less one based on science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM), the heart (xin) is known as the master of all the other organs, and is the source of both physical and mental life. The xin guides all other organs of the body into proper balance, but only when it is perfectly balanced itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xin can be translated as heart, intention, or center; however the full meaning goes beyond the physical heart to describe the place in our body where the spirit and mind reside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In TCM, the heart houses the spiritual aspect of the mind, known as shen. Shen is essential because according to Chinese medical principles dating back over 2,000 years, the physical and emotional heart are not separate; they are interwoven partners in a balanced body.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>